SUMMARY

Entry-level web developer skilled in several coding languages including HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, PHP, and SQL. Has been taking online courses on web development for over 2 years and created two personal websites; my primary one being *www.michaelfrederickson.net*. Worked as an office manager and associate for over 3 years and has gathered a lot of experience with corporate software including Order Entry, Sales Force, Microsoft Office, and more.

CODING SKILLS

HTML5

- Child/parent structures
- Nested lists
- Anchor tags, hrefs
- Emmet
- Class & ID management
- LinkedIn Frontend Knowledge Badge

CSS3

- Flexbox, CSS grid
- Mobile optimization
- Media queries
- Animations & transitions
- Positioning (relative, fixed, etc.)
- Bootstrap

JavaScript

- Loops, for loops, etc.
- Event listeners
- Functions, callbacks
- Arrays & objects
- jQuery
- Prototype functionality
- Template literals & concatenation

PHP

- Looping structures, Arrays
- Variable syntax
- Console commands
- String syntax, concatenation

SQL

- Database seeding
- · Inserting, updating, and deleting rows/data
- Retrieving specific entries
- Customizing queries for clearer data presentation

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

Technical Skills

- Microsoft Office
- Order Entry
- · Sales Force
- 100wpm typing speed

Soft Skills

- Professionalism in communication
- Multitasking
- Teamwork and coordination
- Management and delegation

RECENT EXPERIENCE

Carmax — Business Office Manager / Associate MARCH 2015 - AUGUST 2019

MedMo — Clerk AUGUST 2019 - FEBRUARY 2020

Purple — Machinist / Document Specialist AUGUST 2020 - DECEMBER 2022

EDUCATION

Northwest Career & Technical Academy — High School Diploma — Major in Engineering Online Courses (Rithm, TeamTreehouse CodeSmith, etc.) — Has been studying online courses for web development for over two years including courses on HTML, JavaScript, CSS, AJAX, PHP, and SQL. Currently attending Rithm School to learn Python, TypeScript, React, AJAX, AWS, and more.

Personal website: www.michaelfrederickson.net

References

Curtis Black

Senior Software Developer & Team Lead — Descartes (702)-715-2022 Coding Mentor

Elizabeth Frederickson

Help Desk Manager — DentalCMO (702)-353-2031
Sister & Mutual Coding Think-Tank

Solomon Hailemelekot

Sales Manager — Carmax (702)-824-0286 Formerly an Office Manager at Carmax

Taylor Silvey

Dealership Specialist — Desert 215 Superstore (702)-528-2561

Formerly an Office Manager at Carmax

Austin Davis

Innovations Lead — Purple (801)-906-1779
Formerly a Site Manager at Purple

Timothy Knight

Business Office Manager — Carmax (602)-796-1175

Also known as "Timpossible"